Make money while we’re training?
At the Heavens Arena.
Heavens Arena…?
Yeah! I’ll explain later.
But we really ought to get going now!
[Gon] Right!
[theme song playing]
Whoa! Look, it’s huge!
Yep.
That’s Heavens Arena.
It’s two 251 stories,
and 991 meters tall,
making it the world’s fourth
tallest building.
So, this is where we’ll be training…
Well, the tickets
we bought to get us here,
left us completely broke.
We’ve gotta make more while we’re here.
We’ll start fresh when we disembark.
Right! I got it.
All right. Well? Let’s go!
[Gon] Okay!
ARRIVAL x AT x THE ARENA
[narrator] Gon and Killua
head to Heavens Arena
with only one goal in mind:
to get stronger.
[Killua] Gon.
[Gon] This is a really long line.
Is everyone going to Heavens Arena?
There aren’t any rules to worry about.
Not like there were for the Hunter Exam.
You just gotta knock your opponent out.
Oh…
The higher you go,
the more prize money you make.
If you want to earn a living
with your fists,
this is as good as it gets!
[receptionist] Welcome to Heavens Arena.
Now, if you wouldn’t mind
filling out this form…
Killua Zoldyck, you’re number 2054.
Gon Freecss, you are 2055.
On the first arena floor,
they’ll be calling you by your number,
so try not to forget it.
Please go on ahead.
[cheering]
Wow…!
[grunting]
-Looking good!
-Do it!
It's been a while,
but the place hasn't changed.
Wait… you mean you’ve been here before?
Yeah. When I was about six.
My dad left me here flat broke.
Told me to reach 200th floor.
Took me two whole years.
Two years?
I mean, sure, he was only six…
but it took him that long?
There are guys of Hisoka’s caliber
but only farther up, so don’t waste time.
-Ya got it?
-Uh-huh.
[announcer] Numbers 1973 and 2055.
to ring E.
2055! That's me!
Oh, man, I’m getting pretty nervous
right about now.
Gon. You made it
through the Testing Gate, right?
Hm?
So, relax.
[man 1] Check it out! It’s just a kid!
[man 2] Hey!
Ya better run while you still can, kid!
[man 3] This ain’t a game!
Give him a punch and send him flying!
This is a first-floor fight
so we will be appraising
your skill levels.
You’re allowed three minutes
to demonstrate
what you’re capable of.
Now then… Begin!
-I’m real sorry, kid.
-[flexing knuckles]
But I’ll make it fast,
so you don’t have to suffer!
You made it
through the Testing Gate, right?
So, relax! Go out there and push hard!
Okay, so just…
push hard!
[screams]
No way!
Nice!
[impressed callouts]
[man 2] That kid’s incredible!
[man 1] What crazy power!
When did I get so strong?
2055, proceed directly to floor 50.
Okay!
[impressed callouts]
[man 2] Look at that!
That first kid’s not the only one
who’s a beast!
[beeping]
Wait.
This says you’ve already been
to the 200th floor?
And those were some powerful moves.
All right. Go to the 180th floor--
Nah. I’ll start at 50.
[referee] Huh?
I want to take it slow.
[impressed callouts]
[referee] Enough!
[man 1]
Whoa! That kid’s pretty powerful, too!
You’re permitted to advance
to the 50th floor.
Osu! Thank you!
[female guide]
The first 200 floors of Heavens Arena
are divided into classes, ten floors each.
Which means that a fighter
who wins on the 50th floor,
advances to the 60th.
Lose and they automatically drop down
to the 40th floor.
[Gon] So that’s how it works…
[Killua] Also…
I’ve heard once you get all the way
to the 100th floor,
they comp you your very own room!
Oh! I’m sorry, how impolite!
Osu! My name is Zushi!
And you?
I'm Killua.
My name’s Gon.
Nice to meet you.
-[elevator dings]
-[guide] Here we are.
[Zushi] Oh, I watched your fights earlier.
You guys are amazing!
What are you talking about?
You made it up here
with only one match, too.
He’s right!
No, no.
I still have a long way to go.
By the way,
what discipline do you practice?
I study the Shingen-ryu technique.
A discipline? Don’t have one.
Nope.
You’re kidding!
You’re both that powerful
with no formal training?
I’m humbled to be in your presence.
I’ve come a long way,
but I’m not finished!
[someone clapping their hands.]
[man] Zushi!
You did well.
Thank you, Master!
I’m very happy to see
that you stuck to my teachings.
Osu! I am honored.
But Master your shirt’s untucked.
Oh! Sorry about that.
[nervous giggle]
Who are they?
Oh. This is Killua and Gon.
Pleasure to meet you.
My name is Wing.
[both] Osu!
I really wasn’t expecting
to see any other kids here
besides Zushi.
So, what brings the two of you here?
Uh, we--
well, we want to become stronger.
But we’re also pretty broke,
so we’re making money
at exactly the same time.
Yeah. Killua’s been here before, sir.
That right?
You must be quite talented
or else you wouldn’t have made it
to this level.
Even so, pay close attention
to your opponent’s body and your own.
[both] Osu!
[female staffer]
Killua, Gon, and Zushi. Ah, there we are.
Hand me your tickets, please.
Here. This is your prize money
from the earlier fight.
152 jenny...
On this floor, you make just enough
for a juice, win or lose.
But on all of the other floors here
a loss gets you nothing.
Winning on the 50th floor
earns fifty thousand.
Fifty thousand?!
That’s a lot of money!
The 100th floor,
I think you get a million.
Once you're past the 150th floor,
you get ten million.
Ten million?
Didn’t you make it to 200th floor before?
Whoa! The 200th floor?
[Gon] How much do you get
for winning on the 200th floor?
To tell the truth,
I don’t actually know that.
because I quit pretty
much as soon as I qualified for it.
But when I won on the 190th floor,
I had around 200 million in total.
Two hundred...
Where's that money now?
[Killua] That was four years ago,
so it’s long gone by now.
I spent all of it on snacks!
That much on snacks in four years?
What kind of snacks were they?
Hey. Let’s head up to the waiting room.
We got through our matches unscathed
on the first floor.
They’ll probably give us
another one today.
Well, if these guys are our opponents,
it’ll be a cinch.
Just take it easy.
Really?
-Killua!
-[quiet grumble]
Quiet! They can hear you!
[announcer] 2054, Mister Killua.
Hey, I’m already up.
[announcer] And 1963, Mister Zushi.
Huh?!
[announcer]
Please head to Arena A on the 57th floor.
Okay.
Osu! I am honored to face you!
I bet. Well, you can’t win ‘em all.
Better luck next time, right?
Catch ya later, Gon.
Yeah. Best of luck to both of you guys!
I’ll wait on the floor above. Bye.
[Gon] ‘kay!
He didn’t have to act
like it was such a done deal.
[commentator] All right, everyone!
This is the event
you’ve all been waiting for!
A unique match-up between two young boys
who’ve both got something to prove!
But don’t underestimate these fighters!
Both had strong showings
in their first rounds
and now they’ve jumped all the way up here
to the 50th floor!
ZUSHI - KILLUA
And now let’s take a look
at the big screen
for the playback of those events!
Killua beat his opponent in a flash!
One chop was all it took to knock him out!
Zushi used martial arts
to punish his opponent
scoring a flawless knockout
against a giant weighing
over 200 kilograms!
Okay now, everyone!
Ready to press your wager buttons?
Go on! Make your picks right now!
[jingle]
[commentator] All the bets are in,
and we have a clear favorite! Zushi!
[irked grumble]
[commentator] Maybe his knowledge
of martial arts has given him the edge!
[Zushi] This isn’t good…
Killua is mad.
Three rounds!
Three minutes per round
decided by points or K.O.!
Begin!
[Killua] I see.
His stance doesn’t leave many openings.
He’s trained hard to master it.
But he doesn’t stand a chance against me.
[commentator] Wow! Killua is walking
boldly toward his opponent!
[strangled cry]
[Killua] Sorry, but I’m sticking
to one chop per match
‘til I reach the 150th floor.
A clean hit!
[commentator] Killua has laid out
another opponent with a single blow!
A clean hit and a knockout
earn him two points!
As you know
under the points and knockout system,
there are clean hits,
critical hits, and knockdowns.
Great attacks count as ‘clean hits’,
worth one point each.
Superb attacks are ‘critical hits’,
and are worth two points.
Knocking your opponent down is one point.
Collect ten points and you’re awarded
a technical knockout.
Of course, if your opponent
can’t continue the fight after one hit
you win by knockout!
[Killua] Pretty sure that chop ended it.
Idiot.
Can you fight?
Yes! I’m all right!
[commentator] He got up!
Zushi will continue the match!
And begin!
[Killua] Did I hold back too much?
[Zushi grunting]
[Zushi roars]
[cries out]
[commentator] He’s taken another hit!
Zushi is down!
But he’s getting up
before the referee reaches him,
meaning Killua won’t be awarded the point!
[grunts] He’s good.
I’ll have to change my tactics.
But something’s not right.
That attack was so strong
that even if I just grazed him,
he’d be out cold.
[Zushi] Unbelievable!
Such awesome power and speed!
At this rate, I won’t stand a chance!
But I’ve gotta try.
I have to!
[commentator] Uh-oh! What’s happening?
It looks like Killua is on the run!
[yells] Zushi!
[commentator] So...
a very loud and overenthusiastic spectator
has temporarily interrupted the fight
but let’s see
if we can get it going again!
Come on folks, whaddya say?
ELEVATOR
[elevator dings]
Oh, hey! Killua!
Over here!
Check it out! I got 60000.
How about you?
It took you longer to get here
than I expected.
Yeah, I ran into some trouble.
So, was Zushi pretty strong?
Or what?
No way… No.
He has potential.
He’ll be strong one day.
For now, anyway,
he’s just target practice for me.
Punches that weak,
I could knock him around easy.
But I couldn’t beat him.
Huh?
I won the match.
TKO by points.
But still I just couldn’t knock him out.
Also…
When he changed his stance,
I got this real creepy feeling,
like when I face my brother.
I don't know what it was,
but it felt... dangerous.
It’s gotta be some kind of technique.
I heard his master
call it ‘Ren’.
[Zushi] Please! Forgive me, Master!
[Wing] I thought I made it clear to you
that you were not supposed
to use Ren yet, Zushi.
[Zushi] I’m sorry!
It’s just... he-- he was so strong,
I couldn't help myself.
Yes. I understand the urge to win.
But you have another goal.
A goal that lies beyond this.
At the top floor of this tower.
Don’t focus too much
on simply winning, Zushi.
Impatience will only erode your potential.
Osu!
You must be prepared to lose
a thousand times while you’re here.
[Zushi] Osu!
So, he’s not supposed to use Ren?
Until he gets all the way up
to the top floor, I mean?
That’s where
the strongest fighters are, right?
At the top?
Gon. We need to change our plan.
Huh?
I say we shoot for the top floor.
Right!
Actually, that’s been my plan
this whole time!
-[crowd cheering]
-[fighter grunts]
[commentator]
Killua defeats another opponent
with one chop for a knockout win!
Now there’s action over in the next arena.
Gon has knocked out another opponent
with a single push!
Each of them has won
six consecutive matches
over the past three days,
And they’ve reached the hundreds
without even a scratch to show for it!
[jingle]
Killua's chop.
and Gon’s push.
They seem unstoppable.
But can they keep it up?
But the real question is
who if anyone can stop them?
Yay! Our own room!
[laughing]
We’re not gonna have to worry
about money and lodging anymore!
I wouldn’t be so sure.
Try to remember,
drop below the 100th floor
and you lose the room.
There’s a huge difference
between getting here
and staying here on the 100th floor.
It’s a real threshold.
Threshold?
Beyond the 100th floor,
you get special treatment.
And so, naturally,
no one wants to lose their standing.
There are people here
who’ll do anything it takes
to stay on the 100th floor.
You can waste a lot of time on ‘em.
Time we don’t have right now.
So be careful, Gon.
[crowd cheering]
[commentator]
Gon wins another match with a single push!
[Killua]
Guess I didn’t need to worry about him.
[crowd cheering]
Your prize money has been deposited
into your account.
[Gon] You were right.
I've never seen so many zeros before.
Crazy that just last week,
I was totally broke.
I’m a little bit annoyed.
Huh?
The first time I was here,
it took me two whole months
to reach floor 150.
You, on the other hand...
Yeah, but back then, you were only six.
Well yeah, there’s that.
[Gon] Oh, by the way,
I saw Zushi on TV earlier.
[Killua] Yeah, so did I.
He’s still on the 50th floor.
I wonder what that ‘Ren’ thing was
that creeped you out.
And why.
[Killua] It’s weird, huh?
Hmm...
Maybe we’ll meet
some opponents higher up who use it.
Or maybe...
it’d be faster to just ask Zushi!
Ren is one of the Four Exercises.
The Four Exercises are fundamental
to all martial arts.
They instill discipline
and develop character.
“Learn Ten, know Zetsu,
through Ren to attain Hatsu!”
And all of that is how you train for Nen!
-That’s it!
-Start making sense!
[Wing] Zushi…
Are you certain
that you’re sufficiently qualified
to be teaching others?
Now, Gon, Killua…
An old proverb warns:
that it’s possible
a smattering of knowledge
may not reduce one’s ignorance,
but increase it.
So, you’re saying a little knowledge
is a dangerous thing’?
Thanks for the tip,
but I really want to learn this.
Because I’m convinced
it’s behind my brother’s powers.
You say that your brother...
is able to use Nen?
I need to understand
what Nen and Ren even mean!
And not just halfway.
I need to know it!
If you’re willing to teach me,
I won’t try to figure it out for myself.
Well, in that case…
Let’s adjourn to my room.
[narrator] Questions abound.
What is Nen? What is Ren?
Killua believes they’re related
to his older brother Illumi’s abilities.
Gon wants to know
what these words mean, as well.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Coming up:
-Gon...
-[Killua] ...and Killua’s…
[Gon and Killua] Hunterpedia!
-I’m Gon!
-I’m Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today we’ll be introducing Zushi!
He’s really, really talented.
In fact, he’s considered
one in a hundred thousand!
While Gon and I are
one in a hundred million!
Osu!
[Gon] Next time:
"Nen x And x Nen."
That was a rough one!
[Killua] But you hung in there!
[both] Osu!